<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Hugo González Labrador</title>
    <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Hugo González Labrador</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright Hugo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://labkode.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A journey to the mesh : microservices-based sync and share using gRPC and Protobuf</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/journey-mesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/journey-mesh/</guid>
      <description>CERNBox is a multipetabyte-scale sync and share platform at CERN, storing close to 7 PB of data for more than 16K users. Over time we have identified different improvement points to increase development agility and maintenance costs for running the service. Last year we have evolved the architecture of the service from a monolithic stack to a decentralised model based on micro-services. This mesh is the core of the new system and relies on latest technologies (gRPC and Protobuf) for efficient inter-component communication and controlled API evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How is CERN using the ownCloud?</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/interview-owncloud-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/interview-owncloud-2018/</guid>
      <description>Based on the popular ownCloud open source file sync and share community project, ownCloud was founded in 2011 to give corporate IT greater control of their data — combining greater flexibility, openness and extensibility with on premise servers and storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From application to service development</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/from-app-to-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/from-app-to-service/</guid>
      <description>ownCloud offers a great platform for developing applications that can integrate a variety of services, from document editing apps to image previews and more. After running the CERNBox service for the last 5 years, an ownCloud based cloud sync and share for CERN, we have identified that as more integrations are done in the ownCloud platform more knowledge is needed by the ownCloud operators to manage the platform. In CERNBox, we have introduced a distributed approach to split team responsibilities when developing service integrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is special in CERNBox?</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/special-cernbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/special-cernbox/</guid>
      <description>ownCloud has some design constraints that limits the scalability of the product when is being used in huge deployments. CERNBox is based on ownCloud for providing sync and share to more than 14,000 users. Besides this use case, CERNBox expands the ownCloud platform to provide advance use cases to the scientific community at CERN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CERNBox: the CERN cloud storage hub</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-cloud-hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-cloud-hub/</guid>
      <description>CERNBox is the CERN cloud storage hub. It allows synchronising and sharing files on all major desktop and mobile platforms (Linux, Windows, MacOSX, Android, iOS) aiming to provide universal access and offline availability to any data stored in the CERN EOS infrastructure.
With more than 12000 users registered in the system, CERNBox has responded to the high demand in our diverse community to an easily and accessible cloud storage solution that also provides integration with other CERN services for big science: visualisation tools, interactive data analysis and real-time collaborative editing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Storage for data-intensive sciences in science and industry</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/data-science/</guid>
      <description>In the last few years we have been seeing constant interest for technologies providing effective cloud storage for scientific use, matching the requirements of price, privacy and scientific usability. This interest is not limited to HEP and extends out to other scientific fields due to the fast data increase: for example, &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; is a characteristic of modern genomics, energy and financial services to mention a few.
The provision of cloud storage accessible via synchronisation and sharing interfaces became an essential element of services&amp;rsquo; portfolios offered by research laboratories and universities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating collaborative analysis in SWAN</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/facilitate-swan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/facilitate-swan/</guid>
      <description>SWAN (Service for Web-based ANalysis) is a CERN service that allows users to perform interactive data analysis in the cloud, in a &amp;ldquo;software as a service&amp;rdquo; model. It is built upon the widely-used Jupyter notebooks, allowing users to write - and run - their data analysis using only a web browser. By connecting to SWAN, users have immediate access to storage, software and computing resources that CERN provides, and that they need to do their analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC 2018: Petabyte-Scale Cloud Storage File Manager</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/gsoc-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/gsoc-2018/</guid>
      <description>CERNBox is a cloud storage synchronisation service for CERN users: it allows syncing and sharing files on all major mobile and desktop platforms (Linux, Windows, MacOSX, Android, iOS) aiming to provide offline availability to any data stored in the CERN EOS infrastructure. CERNBox is based on ownCloud, a cloud sync and share platform written in PHP following a Model-View-Controller architecture software pattern.
This project aims to provide a prototype of a new web UI for CERNBox that will provide an immersive user experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Microservice Architecture for CERNBOX</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/eos-cernbox-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/eos-cernbox-microservices/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CERNBox: the CERN cloud storage driven by EOS</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-eos-driven/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-eos-driven/</guid>
      <description>CERNBox is a the CERN cloud storage service. It allows synchronising and sharing files on all major desktop and mobile platforms (Linux, Windows, MacOSX, Android, iOS) aiming to provide universal access and offline availability to any data stored in the CERN EOS infrastructure. With more than 12k users registered in the system, CERNBox has responded to the high demand in our diverse community to an easily and accessible cloud storage solution that also provides integration with other CERN services for big science: visualization tools, interactive data analysis and real-time collaborative editing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CERNBox Service</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-service-krakow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-service-krakow/</guid>
      <description>CERNBox is a cloud synchronisation service for end-users: it allows synchronising and sharing files on all major desktop and mobile platforms (Linux, Windows, MacOSX, Android, iOS) aiming to provide universal access and offline availability to any data stored in the CERN EOS infrastructure. With 12000 users registered in the system, CERNBox has responded to the high demand in our diverse community to an easily and accessible cloud storage solution that also provides integration with other CERN services for big science: visualization tools, interactive data analysis and real-time collaborative editing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future architectures for sync and share based on microservices</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/future-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/future-microservices/</guid>
      <description>Microservices are an approach to distributed systems that promote the use of finely grained services with their own lifecycles, which collaborate. The use of microservices facilitates embracing new technologies and architectural patterns. Sync and share providers could increase the modularity and facilitating the exchange of components and best practices adopting the use of microservices. In CERNBox we have currently started replacing functionality in the monolithic software with small microservices to improve the management of the service and ease the integration with other services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Monolith: An example of microservices for sync and share based on ClawIO</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/breaking-the-monolith/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/breaking-the-monolith/</guid>
      <description>A study of using a distributed microservices architecture for synchronization and sharing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CERNBox: Petabyte-Scale Cloud Synchronisation and Sharing Platform</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-thesis/</guid>
      <description>CERNBox is a cloud synchronisation service for end-users: it allows syncing and sharing files on all major mobile and desktop platforms (Linux, Windows, MacOSX, Android, iOS) aiming to provide offline availability to any data stored in the CERN EOS infrastructure. There is a high demand in the community for an easily accessible cloud storage solution such as CERNBox. Integration of the CERNBox service with the EOS storage back-end is the next step towards providing ’synchronisation and sharing‘ capabilities for scientific and engineering use-cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClawIO: Cloud Synchronisation Benchmarking Framework</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/clawio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/clawio/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the results of the research that led to the development of ClawIO: a cloud synchronisation benchmarking framework. The framework allows to build distributed and highly decoupled cloud File Synchronisation and Sharing platforms in order to obtain performance metrics after being stressed with different test suites. The framework introduces a flexible and extendable layered distributed architecture. We develop a testing scenario for the framework that understands own- Cloud’s synchronisation protocol on top of a local filesystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview with the ownCloud CERN team</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/interview-owncloud-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/interview-owncloud-2016/</guid>
      <description>From the ownCloud Contributor Conference 2015 we spoke with Jakub Moscicki and Hugo Gonzalez from CERN about their usage of ownCloud and thoughts about the ownCloud Contributor Conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing data and metadata backends with ClawIO</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/clawio-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/clawio-talk/</guid>
      <description>Open Source Cloud Sync and Share software provides synchronisation layer on top of a variety of backend storages such as local filesystems and object storage. In case of some software stacks, such as ownCloud, a SQL database is used to support the synchronisation requirements. We tested how different technology stacks impact the ownCloud HTTP-based Synchronisation Protocol. Efficiency and scalability analysis was performed based on benchmarking results. The results have been produced using the ClawIO framework prototype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CERNBox &#43; EOS: end-user storage for science</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-plus-eos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-plus-eos/</guid>
      <description>CERNBox is a cloud synchronisation service for end-users: it allows syncing and sharing files on all major mobile and desktop platforms (Linux, Windows, MacOSX, Android, iOS) aiming to provide offline availability to any data stored in the CERN EOS infrastructure. The successful beta phase of the service confirmed the high demand in the community for an easily accessible cloud storage solution such as CERNBox. Integration of the CERNBox service with the EOS storage back-end is the next step towards providing “sync and share” capabilities for scientific and engineering use-cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disk storage at CERN</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/disk-storage-at-cern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/disk-storage-at-cern/</guid>
      <description>CERN IT DSS operates the main storage resources for data taking and physics analysis mainly via three system: AFS, CASTOR and EOS. The total usable space available on disk for users is about 100 PB (with relative ratios 1:20:120). EOS actively uses the two CERN Tier0 centres (Meyrin and Wigner) with 50:50 ratio. IT DSS also provide sizeable on-demand resources for IT services most notably OpenStack and NFS-based clients: this is provided by a Ceph infrastructure (3 PB) and few proprietary servers (NetApp).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From oc_filecache to an scalable and flexible OwnCloud namespace</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-oc-filecache/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-oc-filecache/</guid>
      <description>ownCloud has some design constraints that limits the scalability of the product when is being used in huge deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CERNBox: To Share or Not to Share</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-share-not-share/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-share-not-share/</guid>
      <description>What is the meaning of collaboration? How can you achieve it with CERNBox? Should you share or not? And how you should share?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The CERNBox Service</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-service/</guid>
      <description>CERNBox is a cloud synchronisation service for end-users: it allows syncing and sharing files on all major mobile and desktop platforms (Linux, Windows, MacOSX, Android, iOS) aiming to provide offline availability to any data stored in the CERN EOS infrastructure. The successful beta phase of the service confirmed the high demand in the community for an easily accessible cloud storage solution such as CERNBox. Integration of the CERNBox service with the EOS storage back-end is the next step towards providing “sync and share” capabilities for scientific and engineering use-cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site report: CERNBox</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/site-report-cernbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/site-report-cernbox/</guid>
      <description>Report on the CERNBox Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CERNBox &#43; EOS: end-user storage for science</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-plus-eos-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/cernbox-plus-eos-talk/</guid>
      <description>CERNBox is a cloud synchronisation service for end-users: it allows syncing and sharing files on all major mobile and desktop platforms (Linux, Windows, MacOSX, Android, iOS) aiming to provide offline availability to any data stored in the CERN EOS infrastructure. The successful beta phase of the service confirmed the high demand in the community for an easily accessible cloud storage solution such as CERNBox. Integration of the CERNBox service with the EOS storage back-end is the next step towards providing “sync and share” capabilities for scientific and engineering use-cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Storage for (Big and Small) Science</title>
      <link>http://labkode.github.io/research/big-small/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://labkode.github.io/research/big-small/</guid>
      <description>Jakub Moscicki’s update on CERNbox provided us with the analysis of the interesting use-case. The systems that already exist at CERN are supposed to still store massive volumes of data (10s PBs), while robust and effective synchronisation will be possible for selected data sets, e.g. the directory with the computations output data. Jakub also and shared the service usage statistics: 700 users, 3TBs of space used by 6M of files. Feedback from users is very positive, according to Jakub, including ownCloud look and feel and performance observed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>